Finding Aid for the William Lofland Dudley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
William Lofland Dudley Papers
1882-1915
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0123
2.52 linear_feet
William L. Dudley: A Chronology
April 16, 1859 Born in Covington, Kentucky
1879 Isolated a new volatile alkaloid, "spigelina."
1880 B.S. from University of Cincinnati.
1880 Published "Chemical Examination of Urine."
1880-1881 Demonstrator of Chemistry, Miami Medical College of Cincinnati.
1881-1885 Comissioner of Cincinnati Industrial Exposition.
1881-1887 Professor of Chemistry and Toxicology, Miami Medical College
1885 Honorary Degree Doctor of Medicine from Miami Medical College.
1887 Chair of Chemistry at Vanderbilt University.
1897 Director of Affairs of Tennessee Centennial Exposition
1895 to Retirement (1912?) Dean of Vanderbilt Medical School
1904 Secretary of section of Inorganic Chemistry at International Congress of Arts and Sciences in St. Louis.
1907 Recieved patent for flooring which he designed -- magnesia-cement composition containing cellulose water-proofed with paraffin and asbestos.
1908 Investigation of influence of coal gas on corrosion of wrought-iron pipe laid under Nashville streets.
September 8, 1914 Died in Nashville, Tennessee.
Dates Uncertain: Organized Southern Intercollegiate Athletic
Association, president for 18 years.
Member of Executive Committee of the National
Intercollegiate Athletic Association.
Organizer and President of University Club of Nashville.
Unmarried.
Source of information: Reprint from Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, Vol. 6, No. 10, page 856.
- Correspondence - Outgoing. Thirty Letters Arranged Chronologically, 1899-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Incoming. 386 Letters Arranged Alphabetically, 286 Typed, 100 Holograph., 1896-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2-28)
- Lecture Notes - Holograph. 40 items. Arranged Alphabetically by Title. (Box 2, Folder 29-35)
- Holograph Notes on Various Subjects. Untitled. (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Chemical Lectures. Holograph. (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Papers Read at Various Meetings. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Medical Education in the United States" (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Some Notes on Metallurgy of Aluminium" (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Pythagoras"; "Technical Education Abroad" (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Chemical Analyses. Holograph. One Analysis of stomach contents of W.L. Dudley, among others. (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Roll. One Roll Bool and One List. Roo Book Entitled "Classes in Chemistry in the Miami Medical College." (Box 2, Folder 40)
- One Chemistry Record Small Book, 1910-1914 (Box 2, Folder 40 1/2)
- Printed Lists and Notes. Concerns such things as paper topics, Dudley's original research, iron and steel companies, the electron theory. (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Printed Articles and Speeches - 4 items. One untitled. Other Three are: "Determination of Silver by Sodium Carbonate"; "Intercollegiate Athletics in the South"; "Our Sister Schools." (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Invitation. Fourteen. One photograph of David Dudley Miller, age two years. (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Membership Certificates. Acknowleding Dudley's membership in various clubs and organizations. Six. (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Business Reports - Bills, receipts, accounts, one application for patent of spark arrester. (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
- Articles and Reprints by Dudley. Alphabetically Arranged. (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Papers Relating to Athletics. Lists of players, Certificate of Eligibility, etc. (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Athletics - Business Papers. S.I.A.A. Committee Minutes, Rule Changes, article on "Summer Baseball vs the Amatuer Clause." (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Chemical Laboratory - Blueprints and Business papers; Blueprints of Chemical department at Cornell University; Dudley's file on this material marked "to be destroyed." (Box 3, Folder 57-58)
- Documents, Ordinances - Five. Preamble and Constition of S.I.A.A.; Ordinance for Nashville Subway; Ordinance for Nashville Telephone Co.; Charter of Incorporation for Nashville Telephone Co.; Report on a Purposed Suburban Electric Railway. (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Southern Inter-Collegiate Athletic Association. Pamphlets. (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Constitution and By-Laws, handbooks, and Game rules. (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Southern Inter-Collegiate Athletic Association - Pamphlets. (Box 3, Folder 61-62)
- Athletic Organizations - pamphlets. (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
- Eighth International Congress of Applied Chemistry. Printed Memoradum; Preliminary Announcement; 14 copies of "List of Topics Proposed for Section XI, a, for Eighth International Congress of Applied Chemistry." (Box 3, Folder 65-66)
- Speech. "Provincialism and the Citizenship of Tennessee" by Edward H. Barthell. (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Articles and Reprints by Others. F. W. Clarke, "The Constitution of the Tarrates of Antimony"; Waller Deering, "The Anglosaxon Poets on the Judgement Day"; Ernest Victor Jones, "Tellurium, A Spectographic Study"-2 Copies (Box 3, Folder 68)
- News Bulletins and Specail Report. 13 copies of N.C.A.A. News Bulletin; Specail Report of the Executive Committee of the Alumni Association of Vanderbilt University. (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Memorials - "William Lofland Dudley" by Charles Baskerville; "Lucius S. Merriam" by J. H. Hollander and others; "Gates Phillips Thruston, Jr."; "Hiram A. Vance". (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Bulletins - Cincinnati Section, American Chemical Society; History of the Miami Medical College and of its Faculty and Alumni; Alumni Catalogue Miami Medical College; Petition of the Establishment of a Joint Chapter of Sigma XI at Vanderbilt University and George Peabody College for Teachers; Vanderbilt University Quarterly, Vol. XIV, No. 4. (Box 3, Folder 71-72)
- Newpaper Clippings - Dealing with Athletics (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Newpaper Clippings - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Book. Ohio Mechanics Institute, Historical Sketch (Box 5)
- Scrapbook, 1882-1892 (Box 5)
- Scrapbook. 1892-1897. (Box 5)
- Scrapbook. 1897-1910. (Box 6)
- A 1934 map of Vanderbilt, was separated from this collection, whereabouts now unknown.
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Acklen, Joseph H (1), 7 Aug., 1911. F 2.
  - Acme White Lead and Color Works (A. M. Woodward) (1), 28 Oct. 1911. F 2
  - Acton, Robert (1), 18 June 1896. F 2.
  - Adams, John N. (1), 19 March 1911. F 2.
  - Allan, J. S. (1), 30 June 1911. F 2.
  - Allan, Stockdell (2), 18 July, 31 July 1911. F 2.
  - Alling, Charles Jr. (1), 24 April 1911. F 2.
  - American Sports Publishing Co. (1), 24 August 1911. F 2.
  - Ames, John W. (2), 16 Feb. 1911, 20 Feb. 1911. F 2.
  - Anderson, C. F. (1), 14 Oct. 1911. F 2.
  - Anderson, Milton J. (1), 9 Aug. 1904. F 2.
  - Anderson, S. E. (1), 7 June 1911. F 2.
  - Ayers, A. J. (1), 2 Jan. 1911. F 2.
  - Blakiston, P., Son & Co. (H. G. White) (1), 24 Aug. 1914. F 3.
  - Bondurant, Alexander (1), n.d. F 3.
  - Boyd, Thomas D. (2), 26 Dec. 1904 (to Marion Sims), 6 Jan. 1905 (to B.L. Wiggins). F 3.
  - Bridges, M. O. (5), 21 Aug. 1903, 30 Sept. 1903, 8 Dec. 1903, 16 Dec. 1903, 5 Dec. 1904 (to P.M. Simms). F 3.
  - Briesen, Arthur V. (1), 20 Nov. 1911. F 3.
  - Bromwell, Annie G. (1), 22 March 1911. F 3.
  - Brown, Charles L. (1), 18 Feb. 1899. F 3.
  - Burch, Robert L. (2), 8 Feb. 1899, 4 March 1999. F 3.
  - Burick (?), R. K. (1), 15 Oct. 1911. F 3.
  - Butler, George P. (1), 14 Jan. 1910. F 3.
  - Chappell, F. W. (1), 29 Nov. 1904 (to P. M. Simms). F 4.
  - Clary, John T. (2), 12 March 1904, 17 Dec. 1904. F 4.
  - Cole, Louise H. (1), 15 Feb. 1907. F 4.
  - Collier, F. S. (1), 19 Feb. 1912. F 4.
  - Corson, H. H. (1), 14 Feb. 1899. F 4.
  - Dawson, L. (1), 26 Aug. 1914. F 5.
  - di Beuedetto, L. (2), 17 July 1912, May 1913 (to A. A. Mason). F 5.
  - Dye, J.S. (6), 27 Jan. 1904, 2 Feb. 1904, 8 July 1904, n.d., n.d., n.d., F 5.
  - Edmonds, Richard H. (2), 30 June 1911, 9 Nov. 1911. F 5.
  - Ellis, A Caswell (1), 19 May 1904 (to P. M. Simms) F 5.
  - Fuller, Addie I. (1), 29 May 1911. F 6.
  - Gaunt, R. W. (3), 20 April 1904, 24 May 1904, 10 Dec. 1904. F 6.
  - Gordon, J. R. (1), 16 Feb. 1899. F 6.
  - Gudeman, Edward (1), 18 Nov. 1911. F 6.
  - Hamilton, E. J. (1), 25 May 1904. F 6.
  - Handly, Avery (1), 19 May 1904. F 6.
  - Hanovia Chemical & Mfg. Co. (F. W. Robinson) (1), 25 Aug. 1914 F 6.
  - Head, Charles R. (2), 30 Sept. 1903, 19 Nov. 1904. F 6.
  - Head, J. Allen (4), 16 Dec. 1903, 3 Sept. 1904, 11 Dec. 1904 (to P. M. Simms), 15 Dec. 1904. F 6.
  - Head, John W. (12), 21 March 1903, 30 Sept 1903, 11 May 1904, 16 May 1904, 18 May 1904, F 6. 12 July 1904, 14 July 1904, 26 August 1904, 6 Sept. 1904, 15 Sept. 1904, 12 Dec. 1904, 14 Dec. 1904. F 7.
  - Heisman, J. W. (1), 29 Dec. 1909. F 7.
  - Holmes, Edward T. (1), 17 Jan. 1905. F 7.
  - James, W. A. (1), 31 August 1904 (to W. D. Mooney). F 8.
  - Johnson, Laurence I. (1), 23 Dec. 1911 (to Phi Lambda Delta Alumni). F 8.
  - Jones, Richard (1), 17 June 1904. F 8.
  - Jordan, David Starr (1), 3 Dec. 1909 (to Charles R. Van Hise) F 8.
  - Kerr, Thomas B. (1), 18 Nov. 1911. F 8.
  - Lake, D. (1), 19 June --. F 8.
  - Laudis, W. S. (1), 30 Aug. 1911. F 8.
  - Legate, Ray H. (1), 9 June 1911. F 8.
  - Leggett, Albert E. (1), 8 July 1911 (to S. H. Sheib). F 8.
  - Lewis, L. H. (2), 8 Sept. 1904, 1 Dec. 1904. F 8.
  - Little, A. D. (1), 5 Dec. 1911. F 8.
  - MacMillan Company (1), 8 Nov. 1911. F 9.
  - Maddin, Percy D. (1), 24 Nov. 1911. F 9.
  - Malone, Battle (1), 4 Nov. 1911. F 9.
  - Manufacturers Record (4), 15 June 1911, 11 Nov. 1911, 23 Nov. 1911, 22 Dec. 1911. F 9.
  - Marr, Harrington (1), n.d. F 9.
  - Mather, Stephen T. (1), 6 Nov. 1911. F 9.
  - Mason, A. A. (1), 20 May 1912. F 9.
  - McCabe, W. M. (1), 14 Sept. 1911. F 10.
  - McClain, Anne B. (1), 28 Nov.1904. F 10.
  - McClain, J. Scott (1), 12 Oct. 1904. F 10.
  - McCormack, S. T. (1), 22 Nov. 1911. F 10.
  - McDermott, E. J. (2), 21 Aug. 1911, 18 Nov. 1911. F 10.
  - McGovney, D. O. (1), 20 May 1912. F 10.
  - Mc-Graw-Hill Book Co. (1), 21 Aug. 1911. F 10.
  - McGugin, Dan E. (2), 13 Jan. 1910, 4 Sept. 1911. F 10.
  - Meadow, T. C. (1), 10 Aug. 1911. F 10.
  - Mell, A. W. (1), 15 Aug. 1911. F 10.
  - (Miller), Dudley B. (1), 20 Dec. 1911. F 10.
  - (Monroe), J. Blanc (1), n.d. F 11.
  - Mooney, W. D. (10), 5 Sept. 1903, 7 Sept. 1903, 9 Sept. 1903, 1 Oct. 1903, 4 Oct. 1903, 5 Oct. 1903 (to Ashby Wilkins), 8 Oct. 1903, 1 Sept. 1904, 14 Sept. 1904. F 11.
  - Moore, Edward S. (1), 14 June 1911. F 11.
  - Moore, Margaret S. (1), 9 Oct. 1911. F 11.
  - Moore, Rupert E. (1), 28 Sept. 1911. F 11.
  - Morgan, Henry W. (1), 6 Dec. 1911. F 11.
  - Muckenfuss, A. M. (2), 21 June 1911, 1 July 1911. F 11.
  - National Carbon Company (1), 18 Dec. 1911. F 12.
  - Neiman, Howard S. (2), 24 April 1911, 10 July 1911. F 12.
  - Newman, Willie Betty (1), 16 Feb. --. F 12.
  - Nichols, William (1), 12 Dec. 1911 (to Charles E Munroe). F 12.
  - Nicolson, Frank W. (1), 21 Dec. 1911. F 12.
  - Norton Company (4), 3 June 1911, 19 June 1911, 6 July 1911, 28 July 1911. F 12.
  - Norvell, W. E. Jr. (7), 5 Jan. 1911, 17 March 1911, 22 March 1911, 11 May 1911, 26 Oct. 1911, 22 Nov. 1911, 5 Dec. 1911. F 12.
  - Ober, Birch R. (1), 5 Sept. 1911. F 13.
  - Odell, (?) Allan F. (4), 12 Jan. 1911, 2 May 1911, 8 May 1911, 30 May 1911. F 13.
  - Oden, L. H. (1), 14 Sept. 1911. F 13.
  - Palmour, Oscar (1), 6 June 1911. F 14.
  - Parkinson, Robert H. (3), 24 April 1911, 27 April 1911, 18 Nov. 1911. F 14.
  - Parson, Charles L. (8), 4 Jan. 1911, 11 Jan. 1911, 12 Jan. 1911, 18 Jan. 1911, 21 Feb. 1911, 8 April 1911, 21 Aug. 1911, 5 Sept. 1911. F 14.
  - Peirce, James H. (1), 25 April 1911. F 14.
  - Pennie, John C. (3), 23 Feb. 1911, 22 April 1911, 4 May 1911. F 14.
  - Peoples, James A. (2), 14 Dec. 1911, 17 March 1911. F 14.
  - Pierce, Palmer E. (1), 29 Jan. 1911. F 14.
  - Poe, Floyd (1), 7 Dec. 1904. F 14.
  - Polk, Newton N. (2), 5 May 1911, 25 May 1911. F 14.
  - Potts, Robert J. (1), 28 Dec. 1911. F 14.
  - Power, Frederick B. (1), 13 May 1911. F 14.
  - Priest, Charles (3), 20 March 1911, 24 April 1911, 28 April 1911. F 14.
  - Primos Chemical Co. (1), 18 May 1911. F 14.
  - Prothro (?), Andrew (1), 20 Jan. 1911. F 14.
  - Purdue, A. H. (1), 22 Nov. 1911. F 14.
  - Queneau, A. L. (2), 8 May 1911, 22 Nov. 1911. F 14.
  - Raff, Arthur (2), 13 Jan. 1911, 15 Feb. 1911. F 15.
  - Ramage, Carrie (1), 23 Feb. 1911. F 15.
  - Randle, William N. (2), 17 Jan. 1911, 24 April 1911. F 15.
  - Rankin, -- (1), 1 Feb. 1911. F 15.
  - Rankin, B. Kirk (3), 23 Feb. 1911, 3 April 1911, 7 Sept 1911. F 15
  - Resse, Charles L. (4), 27 April 1911, 29 May 1911, 20 Nov. 1911, 26 Dec. 1911. F 15.
  - Rice, G. E. (4), 3 April 1911, 17 April 1911, 26 April 1911, 1 May 1911. F 16.
  - Rice, L. L. (8), 10 Sept. 1903, 25 Sept. 1903, 30 Sept. 1903, 2 Oct. 1903, 23 April 1904, 2 May 1904, 2 may 1904, 21 May 1904, 8 Dec. 1904. F 16.
  - Richards, Joseph W. (2), 21 Feb. 1911, 22 April 1911. F 16.
  - Richardson, Clifford (3), 22 April 1911, 20 Nov. 1911, 28 Nov. 1911. F 16.
  - Ricks, Williams B. (2), 10 July 1911, 18 Aug. 1911. F 17.
  - Riggs, W. M. (2), 3 Nov. 1904, 19 June 1911. F 17.
  - Rohren, A. L. (1), 20 March 1911. F 17.
  - Roessler & Hasslacher Chem. Co. (5), 19 June 1911, 26 June 1911, 7 July 1911, 13 Nov. 1911, 12 June 1911. F 17.
  - Rose, Ella M. (1), 22 Sept. 1911. F 17.
  - Ross, B. B. (1), 18 Dec. 1911. F 17.
  - Ruhm, H. D. (3), 20 Feb. 1911, 7 March 1911, 9 Dec. 1911. F 17.
  - Rutherford, G. S. (2), 12 Oct. 1911, 18 Oct. 1911. F 17.
  - Schuerman, -- (2), 3 July 1911, 4 Aug. 1911. F 18.
  - Schwartz, H. A. (2), 14 Jan. 1911, 26 Jan. 1911. F 18.
  - Scientific Materials Co. (4), 26 May 1911, 30 June 1911, 27 Sept. 1911, 3 Oct. 1911. F 18.
  - Seay, Eds. (1), 13 June 1911. F 18.
  - Shannon, E. S. (2), 10 Oct. 1911, 13 Oct. 1911. F 18.
  - Shatton, S. W. (1), 21 Feb. 1911. F 18.
  - Sheffield Casting & Manufacturing Co. (1), 13 May 1911. F 18.
  - Sheib, -- (2), -- 16 June 1911, 17 July 1911. F 18.
  - Sheppard, W. G. (1), 27 May 1911. F 18.
  - Sherwin, C. P. (2), 9 Feb. 1911, 26 Feb. 19.. F19.
  - Shwab, George A. (1), 19 June 1911. F 19.
  - Simms, P. M. (12), 20 Nov. 1903, 3 Dec. 1903, 14 May 1904, 13 June 1904, 28 Nov. 1904 (to Frank Chappel); 1 Dec. 1904 (to --- Wiggins), 13 Dec. 1904, 13 Dec 1904 (to percy Whiting), 16 Dec. 1904, 28 Dec. 1904 (to Thomas D. Boyd), 31 Dec. 1904 (to Thomas D. Boyd) 10 Jan. 1905 (to Thomas D. Boyd)
  - Sioussat, St. George L. (10), 3 Jan. 1911, 12 Jan. 1911, 18 Jan. 1911, 5 April 1911, 2 May 1911, 9 May 1911, 22 May 1911, 27 May 1911, 5 June 1911, 12 June 1911. F 20.
  - Slaughter, B. G. Jr. (2), 6 Feb. 1904, 22 July 1904. F 20.
  - Smiser, M. B. (3), 21 Aug 1903, 30 Sept. 1903, 14 Oct. 1903. F 20.
  - Smith, Alexander (2), 13 Feb. 1911, 4 March 1911. F 21.
  - Smith, G. McP. (1), 15 July 1911. F 21.
  - Smith, Paul D. (1), 27 March 1911. F 21.
  - Smith, R. K. (1), 4 June 1911. F 21.
  - Smith, Richard (1), 29 May --. F 21.
  - Synder, J. H. (1), 30 March 1904. F 21.
  - Spain, Frank Edward (1), 18 Jan. 1910. F21.
  - Spencer, C. M. (1), 21 Aug. 1903. F 21.
  - Sportlover (1), 9 Dec. 1903 (to B. L. Wiggins). F 21.
  - Springer, Alfred (6), 18 Feb. 1911, 7 March 1911, 15 April 1911, 20 Nov. 1911, 6 Dec. 1911, 19 Dec. 1911. F 21.
  - Stauffer, Nathan P. (1), 11 Jan. 1911. F 22.
  - Staughton, Bradley (1), 17 Aug. 1914. F 22.
  - Stechert, G. E. & Co. (3), 27 Aug. 1912, 20 Sept. 1912, 2 Aug. 1913, F 22.
  - Stone, George C. (2), 8 Nov. 1911, 21 Dec. 1911. F 22.
  - Stone, J. N. (1), 17 Dec. 1904. F 22.
  - Stokes, Jordan & James Whitworth (1), 12 Dec. 1911. F 22.
  - Stub, D. W. (1), 11 Aug. 1911. F 22.
  - Stubblefield, D. R. (1), 30 Jan. 1911. F 22.
  - Sullivan, James E. (1), 20 July 1911. F 22.
  - Swenson Evaporator Co. (2), 1 Aug. 1911, 31 Oct. 1911. F 22.
  - Takamine, Jokichi (2), 24 April 1911, 23 Dec. 1911. F 23.
  - Tabbot, Charles Homer (1), 9 Nov. 1911. F 23.
  - Tassin, Wirt (1), 20 Dec. 1911. F 23.
  - Thompson, Edward (2), 8 March 1911, 19 March 1911. F 23.
  - Trabue, Charles C. (3), 22 April 1911, 6 Dec. 1911, 20 Dec. 1911. F 23.
  - Trimpe, William A. (7), 18 Feb. 1911 (to William E. Norvell, Jr.), 8 March 1911, 15 March 1911, 20 July 1911, 31 July 1911, 10 Nov. 1911, 18 Dec. 1911. F 23.
  - Turne (?), John Pichen (2), 11 Sept. 1911, 16 Sept. 1911. F 23.
  - Wait, Charles E. (2), 17 April 1904, 29 April 1904. F 24.
  - Walker, Bradley (2), 3 Oct. 1903, 4 Oct 1903. F 24.
  - Walter, H. C. (6), 9 Feb. 1911, 13 March 1911, 18 April 1911, 16 May 1911, 18 May 1911, 19 Aug. 1911. F 24.
  - Wallace, R. James (1), 11 Jan. 1911. F 24.
  - Wannamaker, Olin D. (1), 4 Jan. 1911. F 24.
  - Warner, Percy (1), 10 Feb. 1911. F 24.
  - Washburn, Frank S. (1), 25 April 1911. F 24.
  - Webb, James A. & Son (1), 10 June 1911. F 24.
  - Wellman, Creighton (1), 1 Feb. 1911. F 24.
  - West, S. Nick (2), 16 June 1911, 31 July 1911. F 24.
  - White, E. D. (2), 15 Feb. 1911, 6 Dec. 1911. F 24.
  - White, S. S., Dental Mfg. Co. (1), 16 Jan. 1911. F 24.
  - Whiting, Percy H., 15 Dec. 1904, 15 Dec. 1904 (to P. M. Simms). F 25.
  - Whitney, Casper (1), 11 Jan. 1904. F 25.
  - Whitney, W. R. (2), 8 April 1911, 18 Oct. 1911. F 25.
  - Wiggins, B. L. (5), 7 Oct. 1903, 26 April 1904, 21 May 1904, 3 Dec. 1904 (to P. M. Simms), 21 March 1905. F 25.
  - Wiley, Harvey W. (2), 21 Jan. 1911, n.d. F 26.
  - Wilkins, Ashby (4), 12 Sept. 1903, 26 Sept. 1903, 1 Oct. 1903, 18 Oct. 1903. F 26.
  - Williams, Adele & George (1), 28 June 1911. F 26.
  - Williams, Henry Bo (1), 1 Aug. 1911. F 26.
  - Wilson, Willie R. (1), 21 Jan. 1911. F 26.
  - Winton, W. F. (1), 2 Sept. 1911. F 26.
  - Witt, -- (1), 30 June 1911. F 26.
  - Woldenberg & Schaar (2), 20 April 1911, 27 April 1911. F 26.
  - Wood, Hilliard (1), 1 Aug. 1911. F 26.
  - Woodrow, M. F. (1), 20 Feb. 1911. F 26.
  - Wyeth, George A. (1), 25 Oct. 1911. F 26.
  - Yoe, John H. (1), 15 May 1963 (to David Kaser) F 27.
  - Young, B. E. (3), 30 June 1911, 1 July 1911, 3 July 1911. F 27.
  - Young, J. W., Jr. (1), 6 Sept. 1911. F 27.
  - illegible - 13, Oct. 1903, 22 March 1904, 2 Feb. 1911, 24 July 1911, 9 Oct. 1911. F 28.
  - incomplete or no signature -, 14 Jan. 1911 ( to A. G. Smith), 20 July 1911 (from Harry), 4 Aug. --. F 28.
- Outgoing Correspondence
  - There are twenty-four letters covering a period from 1899 to 1912.
  - All can be found in folder one.
  - R. H. Dudley, 8 Aug., 1899
  - L. L. Rice, 10 Sept., 1903
  - Ashby Wilkins, 10 Sept., 1903
  - Ashby Wilkins, 14 Sept., 1903
  - Ashby Wilkins, 20 Sept., 1903
  - Charles R. Head, 28 Sept., 1903
  - John W. Head, 28 Sept., 1903
  - L. L. Rice, 28 Sept., 1903
  - Ashby Wilkins, 28 Sept., 1903
  - L. L. Rice, 2 Oct., 1903
  - Ashby Wilkins, 13 Oct., 1903
  - L. L. Rice, 29 Oct., 1903
  - P. M. Simms, 28 Nov., 1903
  - P.M. Simms, 7 Dec., 1903
  - M. O. Bridges, 11 Dec., 1903
  - Ed. Davis, 19 March, 1904
  - Executive Committee S. I. A. A., 18 April, 1904
  - Executive Committee S. I. A. A., 25 April, 1904
  - L. L. Rice, 30 April, 1904
  - ? April? 1904
  - Bondurant, 13 May, 1904
  - John W. Head, 1 Sept., 1904
  - Executive Committee S. I. A. A., 26 Sept., 1904
  - John Head, 17 Dec., 1904
  - Frank S. Washburn, 26 July, 1909
  - Frank S. Washburn, 27 July, 1909
  - B. K. Rankin, 8 Sept., 1911
  - C. F. Anderson, 17 Oct., 1911
  - Harrington Marr, 17 Oct., 1911
  - A.A. Mason, 22 May, 1912
- The Action of Fused Sodium Dioxide on Metals -, 3 copies. F 48.
- The Action of Gaseous Hydrochloric Acid and Oxygen on the Platinum Metals - 4 copies. F 48.
- The Action of Water on Lead Pipe. F 48.
- Address. F 48.
- Athletic Control in School and College - 11 copies. F 48.
- The Atomic Weight of Tellurium; and Critique of the Basic Nitrate Method of Determination. F 49.
- A Chart for the Chemical Examination of Urine. 4 copies. F 49.
- The Chemists' Club. F 49.
- The Colors and Absorption-Spectra of Thin Metallic Films and of Incandescent Vapors of the Metals; With Some Oberservations of Electrical Volatility. F 49.
- A Curious Occurrence of Vivianite. F 49.
- Detection of Arsenic in Animal Tissues. 2 copies. F 50.
- The Effect of Coal Gas on the Corrosion of Wrought Iron Pipe, Buried in the Earth. 3 Copies. F 50.
- The Electro-Deposition of Iridium; A Method of Maintaining the Uniform Composition of an Electroplating Bath Without the Use of an Anode. F 50.
- The Filtration of Alcoholic Liquids through Wood Charcoal. F 50.
- Holland's Process of Melting Iridium. 2 copies. F 50.
- Iridium - 2 copies. F 50.
- The Iridium Industry. F 50.
- Laboratory Notes. F 50.
- A Lecture Table Down Draft. 2 copies. F 50.
- The Luminosity of Comets. F 51.
- Neon and Electric Waves. 23 Copies. F 51.
- Nickels - Kickelic Hydrate, Ni3O4. 2 H2O. 2 copies F 51.
- A Note on the Production of Catharsis by Means of Hypodermatic Medication. 2 copies. F 52.
- Notes on the Toese Method for the Determination of Fusel Oil, and a Compariosn of the Results by the Allen-Marquardt Method. F52.
- The Pierce Process for the Production of Charcoal, Wood Alcohol, and Acetic Acid. F 52.
- The Poisonous Effects of Cigarett-Smoking. F 52.
- A Process for the Removal of the Lint from Cotton Seed. F 52.
- The Proper Control of Athletics. 3 copies. F 52.
- The Relationship of the Heat of Vaporization of Gases to Their Density and Also to Their Boiling-Point. 2 copies. F 53.
- Report of the Committee on Chemistry Teaching. F 53.
- Some Modifications of the Methods of Organic Analysis by Combustion. 3 copies. F 53.
- Spark Arrester. 8 copies. F 53.
- Special Report of Jurors on the Systems of Electric Lighting. F 54.
- A Spectographic Study of Tellurium. F 54.
- Water Crystallization. F 54.
- Aluminum F 29.
- Analysis of Tridismine? F 29.
- Architecture of the Renaissance. F 29.
- Bimetablisms. F 29.
- Brief Biography of John Adams. F 29.
- Chemical Action. F 29.
- Commercial Importance of Scientific Research. F 30.
- Darwin and His Influence. F 30.
- Discovery of America. F 30.
- Discovery of the Elements. F 30.
- Determination of Phosphorus in Iron. F 30.
- Dyeing. F 30.
- Electricity. F 31.
- Elementary Inorganic Chemistry. F 31.
- Evolution. F 31.
- Explosives. F 31.
- Flame. F 31.
- Gold. F 31.
- Great Epidemics. F 31.
- Gunpowder. F 31.
- History of Progress in Steel-Making. F 32.
- How to Observe. F 32.
- Inorganic Chemistry at Watkins Institue. F 32.
- Lincoln, Abraham F 32.
- Low Temperatures by Artificial Means. F 32.
- Medical Education in the U. S. F 32.
- Mob Law. F 32.
- Nicaragua Canal. F 32.
- Pasteur, Louis F 33.
- Poe, Ed. F 33.
- Progress of Science in the 19th Century. F 33.
- Refrigeration. F 33.
- Relation of Chemistry to Pharmacy. F 33.
- Relation of Science to Religion. F 33.
- Relations of Vol. of Vapor to Vol. of Liquid or Latent Heat. F 33.
- Scientific Research. F 34.
- Theory of Dissolution. F 34.
- Toxicology. F 34.
- Ventilation. F 35.
- The Water We Drink. F 35.